# **Edward Ascan**

Junior software developer with a background in SaaS sales. Passionate about web development processes, learning, and building challenging applications. Previously I worked as a Business Development Representative for a software company and have recently decided to pivot my career and learn how to build software myself. As a recent bootcamp graduate, I'm a quick learner, with strong communication, time management and collaborative skills and I excel in fast-paced environments.

# **PROJECTS**

# **Yalper**

Developed a single page application (SPA) using ReactJS, NodeJS & ExpressJS, which also implements Google Oauth and Cloudinary APIs, to allow users to provide services & regular users to find service providers for their specific needs.

**Front-end**: ReactJS, Axios, HTML, SASS. **Back-end**: NodeJS, ExpressJS, PostgreSQL.

### **Interview Scheduler**

Developed Interview Scheduler - a single page application (SPA) built using ReactJS. This application allows users to book and cancel interviews.

Front-end: ReactJS, HTML, SASS.

Back-end: Node|S, Express|S, PostreSQL.

**Testing**: Jest, Storybook, Cypress.

#### Jungle

Fullstack, multi-page, mini e-commerce application that allows browse items, fill their carts and checkout with Stripe. This project was built with the intention of learning Ruby and Ruby on Rails by implementing new features to an existing application.

Front-end: Javascript, HTML, CSS.

Back-end: Ruby, Rails, ActiveRecord, PostgreSQL.

#### **Mapple**

Developed Mapple - a multipage, fullstack application that saves and manages maps and map locations with tags for users. Maps are organized by interest and can be edited, organized and favourited.

Front-end: Javascript, Ajax, JQuery, HTML, SASS.

Back-end: Node|S, Express|S, PostreSQL.

#### **Tweeter**

Tweeter is a simple, single-page application clone of Twitter. This application was built to practice introductory concepts of SPAs as well as to learn CSS.

Front-end: Javascript, Ajax, JQuery, HTML, CSS.

Back-end: Node|S, Express|S.

edwardascan.com

Toronto, ON edward.ascan@me.com 416-669-7278

#### Github

https://github.com/eascan

#### **LinkedIn**

https://www.linkedin.com/in/edwardascan/

#### **SKILLS**

**Languages:** Javascript, Ruby,

HTML, CSS.

Frameworks, libraries &

**environments:** NodeJS, ReactJS, Ajax, Axios, Rails, JQuery, Bootstrap, SASS, Cypress, Jest,

Mocha & Chai, Storybook.

**Systems & Databases:** SQL, PostreSQL, Git, ActiveRecord.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Sales Development Representative

Synapse, Toronto, 2019-2020.

# Account Manager & Business Development

Flow Water, Toronto, 2018-2019.

#### **Personal Trainer**

GoodLife Fitness, North York, 2017-2018.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Lighthouse Labs**, Fullstack Web Development Diploma, Toronto, 2021

**Queen's University**, Bachelor of Science, Kingston, 2016 **St. Andrew's College**, Ontario Secondary School Diploma, Aurora,

#### **LANGUAGES**

2011

Bilingual: English & Russian.